thetruthbehindthescenes.org 2016-03-20

# Privacy & Cookie Policy - RICHTOPIA

Richtopia group takes the privacy of its users seriously. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our users while providing a personalised and valuable service. This Privacy Policy statement explains the data processing practices of Richtopia businesses. If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at info@richtopia.com

The greatest care has been taken in compiling this website. However, no responsibility can be accepted by Richtopia Ltd, the publishers or compilers for the accuracy of the information presented.

Richtopia.com contains many opinions and is designed to provide accurate and authoritative information. It is presented with the understanding that the writers, the publisher and Richtopia Ltd are not engaged in rendering legal, accounting, investment-planning, or other professional advice. The reader should seek the services of a qualified professional for such advice; the author, the publisher and Richtopia Ltd cannot be held responsible for any loss incurred as a result of specific investments or planning decisions made by readers.

Where opinion is expressed it is that of the writer/editor/contributor and does not necessarily coincide with the editorial views of Richtopia Ltd.

The words expressed in Richtopia.com are opinions and should not be interpreted as financial advice. Our sites contain links to third party sites which are not subject to this privacy policy. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit.

 **Information Collected**

Personal information is collected by the Richtopia companies listed below on behalf of the Richtopia group of companies and its trading entities. Each of these Richtopia companies are registered with the UK’s Information Commission as Data Controllers in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. References in this privacy policy to “Richtopia”, “we”, “us”, “our” or similar refer to the Richtopia group company operating the relevant website and references to “Richtopia sites” refer to any of our websites from which you have accessed this privacy policy.

> Company:The Richtopia Ltd

> Registered Office:111A George Lane, London, E18 1AN 

> Company:Richtopia Ltd

We collect personally identifiable information about you (your “Data”) through:

  * the use of enquiry and registration forms

  * your purchase of any our products or services

  * the provision of your details to us either online or offline.

The elements of your Data that we collect may include:

  * Name

  * Job title

  * Company name

  * Company address, phone and fax number

  * Home address and phone number

  * Mobile telephone number

  * E-mail address

  * Payment details such as credit card information

  * Date of birth

  * Educational history, work experience and other information from your CV if you provide this to us

  * Market research data such as readership patterns

  * Usage statistics

We may also collect information that we request from you regarding your use of our service or that we collect automatically about your visit to our sites. Please see our Cookies Policy for more details.

 **Use and Disclosure of Personal Information**  
We use your Data for purposes which may include:

  * providing our users with a personalised service

  * processing orders, registrations and enquiries

  * conducting market research surveys

  * allowing users to participate in interactive features of our service, where they choose to do so

  * providing reports to our Clients containing information about usage under corporate licenses

  * running competitions, prize draws and promotions

  * providing you with information about products and services we offer (if you agree to receive such information)

  * sharing your Data with third party organisations who offer products or services which we feel may be of interest to you (if you agree to receive such information)

  * contacting you about specific recruitment opportunities if you register search criteria information on our recruitment sites.

  * monitoring compliance with our [Terms and Conditions](http://help.ft.com/tools-services/ft-com-terms-and-conditions/) and [Copyright Policy](http://help.ft.com/tools-services/copyright-policy/)

See our Cookies Policy for more details.

If you wish to receive information about Richtopia group products or services or from other carefully selected organisations about products or services they offer, please indicate your preferences using the consent boxes when providing us with your Data.

We may also disclose your information to business partners and to third party suppliers we engage to provide services which involve processing data on our behalf, successors in title to our business or in accordance with a properly executed court order or as otherwise required to do so by law. We reserve the right to fully co-operate with any law enforcement authorities or court order requiring or requesting us to disclose the identity or other usage details of any user of our sites.

We also use information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified by name):

  * to build up marketing profiles

  * to aid strategic development

  * to manage our relationship with advertisers

  * to audit usage of the site.

We use technology on the registration, subscription and manage my account pages of some of our websites, which may record user movements, including page scrolling, mouse clicks and text entered. It will not record financial information such as credit or debit card details. The data we collect in this way helps us to identify usability issues, to improve the assistance and technical support we can provide to users and is also used for aggregated and statistical reporting purposes.

 **Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Devices**

Please refer to our Cookies Policy.

 **Security Policy**

Richtopia businesses have appropriate measures in place to ensure that our users’ Data is protected against unauthorised access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss. User Data may be transferred outside the Richtopia group to data processors such as fulfilment houses but they will act only on our instructions to provide the services required.

 **Transfer of Data**

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore, by browsing the Richtopia sites and communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way. By agreeing to our transfer of your Data to third party organisations for them to send you details of products and services offered (as detailed above) you are deemed to provide your consent to any transfer of your Data to organisations based outside the European Economic Area.

 **User Access and Control of Data**

If you wish to amend any of the Data which we hold about you, or update your marketing preferences, please contact info@Richtopia.com visit the “Contact Us” section of our website.

Investors Chronicle

If you are a user of www.Richtopia.com and you wish to amend any of the Data which we hold about you, or update your marketing preferences, please contact info@Richtopia.com,

All users

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, you may request a copy of the personal information we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer by e-mail at privacy.officer@Richtopia.com or writing to:

Company Secretary The Richtopia Ltd 111A George Lane, London, E18 1AN  United Kingdom

We may charge the statutory allowable fee for provision of this information.

 **Children Under 14**

We do not intentionally collect any information on children under 14 years of age. We will undertake to delete any details of such users where a parent or guardian has notified us that any such details have been obtained.

 **Changes to this Policy**

This policy is effective from 15th December 2014\. From time to time we may make changes to this privacy policy statement to reflect any changes to our privacy practices in accordance with changes to legislation, best practice or website enhancements.

We use cookies and similar tools across our websites to improve their performance and enhance your user experience. This policy explains how we do that.

 **What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text files which a website may put on your computer or mobile device when you first visit a site or page. The cookie will help the website, or another website, to recognise your device the next time you visit. Web beacons or other similar files can also do the same thing. We use the term “cookies” in this policy to refer to all files that collect information in this way.

There are many functions cookies serve. For example, they can help us to remember your username and preferences, analyse how well our website is performing, or even allow us to recommend content we believe will be most relevant to you.

Certain cookies contain personal information – for example, if you click to “remember me” when logging in, a cookie will store your username. Most cookies won’t collect information that identifies you, and will instead collect more general information such as how users arrive at and use our websites, or a user’s general location.

 **What sort of cookies does the Richtopia use?**

Generally, our cookies perform up to four different functions:

1\. Essential cookies

Some cookies are essential for the operation of our website. For example, some cookies allow us to identify subscribers and ensure they can access the subscription only pages. If a subscriber opts to disable these cookies, the user will not be able to access all of the content that a subscription entitles them to.

2\. Performance Cookies

We utilise other cookies to analyse how our visitors use our websites and to monitor website performance. This allows us to provide a high quality experience by customising our offering and quickly identifying and fixing any issues that arise. For example, we might use performance cookies to keep track of which pages are most popular, which method of linking between pages is most effective, and to determine why some pages are receiving error messages. We might also use these cookies to highlight articles or site services that we think will be of interest to you based on your usage of the website.

3\. Functionality Cookies

We use functionality cookies to allow us to remember your preferences. For example, cookies save you the trouble of typing in your username every time you access the site, and recall your customisation preferences, such as which regional edition of the website you want to see when you log in.

We also use functionality cookies to provide you with enhanced services such as allowing you to watch a video online or comment on a blog.

4\. Behaviourally Targeted Advertising Cookies

The Richtopia and our advertisers use cookies to serve you with advertisements that we believe are relevant to you and your interests. For example, if you read a number of articles on motoring on Richtopia.com or on other sites, a car manufacturer might infer you are interested in this topic and serve you with its car advertisements. You might see these advertisements on Richtopia.com and on other sites that you visit. However, we do not tell our advertisers who you are.

 **Does anyone else use cookies on Richtopia websites?**

Advertisers sometimes use their own cookies to provide you with targeted advertising. For example, advertisers may use a profile they have built on sites that you have previously visited to present you with more relevant advertisements during your visit to Richtopia.com. We believe that it is useful to our users to see advertisements that are more relevant to their interests. If you are based in the European Union and would like to learn more about how advertisers use these types of cookies or to choose not to receive them, please visit www.youronlinechoices.eu. If you are based in the United States and would like to learn more, please visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.

We also use or allow third parties to serve cookies that fall into the four categories above. For example, like many companies, we use Google Analytics to help us monitor our website traffic. We may also use third party cookies to help us with market research, revenue tracking, improving site functionality and monitoring compliance with our terms and conditions and copyright policy.

 **Can a website user block cookies?**

As we’ve explained above, cookies help you to get the most out of our websites.

The first time you accessed our website Richtopia, you should have seen an overlay which explained that by continuing to access our site, you are consenting to our use of cookies.

However, if you do wish to disable our cookies then please follow the instructions on our “[How to Manage Cookies](http://help.ft.com/tools-services/how-to-manage-cookies/)” page.

Please remember that if you do choose to disable cookies, you may find that certain sections of our website do not work properly

 **Do we track whether users open our emails?**

Our emails may contain a single, campaign-unique “web beacon pixel” to tell us whether our emails are opened and verify any clicks through to links or advertisements within the email. We may use this information for purposes including determining which of our emails are more interesting to users, to query whether users who do not open our emails wish to continue receiving them and to inform our advertisers in aggregate how many users have clicked on their advertisements. The pixel will be deleted when you delete the email. If you do not wish the pixel to be downloaded to your device, you should select to receive emails from us in plain text rather than HTML.

 **More Information**

More detail on how businesses use cookies is available at www.allaboutcookies.org.

If you have any queries regarding this Cookie Policy please contact our Privacy Officer by e-mail at info@Richtopia.com

This document was last updated on 15th December 2014.
